webperspectives.ca 2015-03-22

# Privacy Statement | Web Perspectives - Web Perspectives

The Web Perspectives website is owned and operated by Research Now Limited, a UK company, ("Research Now"). Research Now Group, Inc. (formerly known as e-Rewards, Inc.)  (a US company), e-Rewards Europe Limited (a UK company), Research Now, Inc. (a US company), Research Now Limited (a UK company), The Mobile Panel Ltd., The Mobile Channel Ltd., Research Now Pty Ltd. (an Australian company), Research Now Inc. (a Canadian company), Research Now Consulting Co. Ltd (a Chinese company), Research Now Technology EPE (a Greek company), Research Now GmbH (a German company), Research Now PTE  LTD (a Singaporian company), Research Now Pty Limited (a New Zealand company), Research Now Spain S.L. (a Spanish company) and Research Now SARL (a French company) together form the Research Now group. This Privacy Statement governs the website located at www.webperspectives.ca.  

Research Now is a provider of Internet-based market research services to professional market research organizations and their clients. The objective of this research is to better understand respondents' opinions. We aggregate and de-identify such research before analyzing and sending the results to our clients.  The information gathered helps our clients develop and design products and services for consumers. In addition, certain survey findings might be published on our websites (in a non-identifiable form) so that our survey respondents can be among the first to hear about the concerns and interests of people around the world.  We are committed to maintaining the privacy of our online respondents and panel members. Our contact information appears below. 

1.    Our Standards

Research Now supports and strictly adheres to the standards and guidelines set out by the Canadian Marketing Research and Intelligence Association of Canada (MRIA) <http://mria-arim.ca/about-mria/what-is-mria> and the World Association of Research Professionals (ESOMAR) [http://www.esomar.org/ ](http://www.esomar.org/)for Internet and other types of research. They can be reviewed at the websites of these associations. These standards protect the interests and privacy of respondents, and also outline our responsibilities to our clients.

Research Now is a licensee of the BBB Privacy Program. BBB is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.webperspectives.ca. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by BBB.

 **2.     Collection & Use of Personal Information **

Research Now only collects personal information directly from our users through our web site to occasionally invite them to participate in surveys relevant to them. Users join our panel voluntarily to voice their opinions regarding products and services.

 **User Registration**

To participate in surveys, you must first register with webperspectives.ca by completing the online registration form. During registration, you are required to provide certain minimum contact information such as your name and email address. We use this information to email you invitations to online research surveys. 

Once you have successfully registered, you will receive an email confirmation to welcome you to webperspectives.ca. Occasionally, we will send you invitations to participate in surveys for which you have been selected.

You also have the option to provide demographic information such as age, gender, address information, household income, working status and education to us.  This information will be used for the purposes of analyzing demographic information in the aggregate, and to identify the surveys that would be most relevant to your interests.  We will never ask for sensitive financial information or your social insurance number. 

On behalf of our clients, we also use web browser-based cookie technology to determine which of our clients’ advertisements have been displayed to you on other websites for the purposes of developing a representative sample of panel participants.  We also use cookie technology for the purposes of ensuring the integrity of our survey data, and to enforce Research Now’s policies.  Depending upon your browser, you can often the disable cookie functionality, if you wish, though we highlight that certain features on our website may be unavailable to browsers that reject cookies.  If you wish to opt-out of the portion of our research services relating to your interaction with our clients’ advertisements on third party web sites, please e-mail us using the contact form available on the [Contact page](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/contact/contact-new/)

**Surveys and Contests**

Occasionally, we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personal information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to provide this information. This typically includes contact information such as email address, and demographic information such as postal code, age, gender, household income etc., as well as questions seeking opinions and feedback that are specific to the subject matter of the survey.

If you are selected as eligible to win one of our contests, we will contact you by email to notify you.  Your mailing address will be used solely for the purposes of mailing a cheque earned as a result of participating in specific surveys or a contest.

 **3.     Disclosures of Personal Information**

We DO NOT give, sell, or otherwise transfer your personal information to third parties without your prior consent, except as otherwise set out below.

 **Survey Responses:  ** Your responses to survey questions are combined with those of other people and are tabulated only in the aggregate. Only non-identifiable and aggregated data will be shared with our clients.  Any answers you provide to survey questions will remain entirely confidential.

 **Service Provider Arrangements:  ** We may transfer (or otherwise make available) your personal information to our affiliates and other third parties who provide services on our behalf.  For example, we may use service providers to host our website, operate certain of its features, serve advertisements on our Website(s), send e-mails, run our contests and promotions, conduct research, manage and analyze data and our advertising effectiveness, and process payments to which individuals are entitled in exchange for completing our surveys.

 **Sale of a Business:  ** We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of our business or as part of a corporate reorganization or other change in corporate control.

 **Legal:**   Research Now and our service providers must provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by law. We may also disclose personal information to assist us in collecting a debt owed by you, or otherwise where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

 **4.     Access and Correction of Personal Information**

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in the personal information we have in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. 

You may request access to your personal information by e-mail using the contact form available on the [Contact page](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/contact/contact-new/) or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below.

If your personal information changes, you may update your information through our website by loging into your account by clicking on [the member login page.](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/member-login/)

 **5.     Opting-out of Receiving Future Survey Invitations**

If you no longer wish to receive our survey invitations, you may opt-out by simply replying to an invitation with "Unsubscribe" in the subject line. You may also opt-out by e-mail using the Contact form available on the [Contact page](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/contact/contact-new/), or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below.

 **6.     Security and Retention of Personal Information**

We have implemented measures in an effort to maintain the security of the personal information in our custody and control, including providing access to personal information to only those employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Website Privacy Statement. 

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control.  Unfortunately, no collection or transmission of information over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and therefore, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any such information in transit.

 To provide you with an increased level of security, online access to certain personal information is protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication (including unsolicited correspondence such as letters, phone calls or e-mail messages).

We keep the personal information of our survey respondents for as long as it remains necessary the purposes stated above or to otherwise meet legal requirements. Our website and your personal information may be maintained on computer systems located outside of Canada.

 **7.     Changes to the Website Privacy Statement**

This website privacy statement may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal information practices. The revised Privacy Statement will be posted on this website. We will use and disclose your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Statement in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise consent or as is permitted by law.

 **8.     Additional Website Information**

We use a technology called “cookies” on our website.  Cookies are widely used across the most popular parts of the internet.  These small amounts of data received by a web browser when a user visits a site enable us to perform certain functions, such as ensuring that potential survey respondents are not sampled more than once.  These cookies are temporary and will automatically expire after the survey is complete. If you wish, depending on your browser, you can also disable the cookie functionality. Please note that if you do disable cookies certain survey and website functionality may not work properly so we recommend that you do not disable cookies in your web-browser.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information that you submit while visiting our site.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, please email us using the contact form available on the [Contact page](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/contact/contact-new/)

**Advanced Cookies**

The advanced cookie tracks the online patterns of Web Perspectives Members. The advanced cookie, which may be placed by Web Perspectives or in conjunction with a third party, incorporates a key which can identify tags contained in certain online content relating to our clients and their products and services.

If a Web Perspectives Member views a page containing any content that includes the tag, the key will send Web Perspectives an update confirming that the Member has viewed the page containing this content. 

In addition, some advanced cookies can be used to target you with advertisement related to research for ad-effectiveness. These advertisements will only be displayed for research purposes and not for Research Now-specific advertising or advertising campaigns unrelated to a specific research projects.

Certain Web pages or Web-based advertisements that you view may be tagged by Research Now, and in some cases, data collected on tagged content may be combined with survey answers that you provide. For example, when you visit or click on our third-party partners' Web sites or online advertisements these events are recorded by Research Now or one of our technology partners, which in turn reports the data to us. We provide that data directly, or combine it with the other information that you provide us with, such as your survey responses and demographic information (but not with your personally identifiable information), to provide market research analysis and data delivery services to our clients, technology partners, and/or Rewards Partners and Marketing Partners. You can opt out of our technology partners' own data collection and ad targeting [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp), [here](http://aboutads.info/choices) or [here](http://preferences.truste.com/truste). If you delete cookies on your browser after opting out, you will have to opt out again. 

You can opt out of receiving such advanced cookies on your device via Web Perspectives by emailing us using the [contact form](https://www.webperspectives.ca/eng/contact/contact-new/). Of course, if a cookie is one that a Web Perspectives Member may receive from a third party, regardless of the Member's participation in the Web Perspectives, then opting out with Web Perspectives will not prevent the Member from receiving that third party's cookie. We neither have access to, nor control over, third-party cookies or how they may be used. Likewise, if the cookie is placed by a third party, we have no control over the nature of the content with which these tags are included. If you would like more information about third-party use of cookies and about your option not to accept these cookies, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Your access to our Web sites will not be affected if you do not accept cookies placed by third parties.

**9.     Contact Information**

If you have any questions about Web Perspectives / Research Now or our Website Privacy Statement, please contact us at the following address:

Jennifer White, Research Manager  
Web Perspectives / Research Now  
250 Yonge Street, Suite 1800  
Toronto, Ontario  
M5B 2L7 

**For more about BBB please[click here](https://www.bbb.org/online/consumer/cks.aspx?ID=1081202142727).**

Effective Date: October 21, 2014
